EMILY ELDO

Mobile: +44 7741088210 Email: emilyeldo@outlook.com linkedin.com/in/emily-eldo-0a005515a

PROFILE

A software testing professional with 7 years of experience in IT services. Currently pursuing MSc in Computing and I am eager to leverage both industry experience and ongoing academic pursuits to drive innovation and excellence in software testing and development.

SKILLS

-Selenium WebDriver -TestNG -BDD Cucumber -Extent Report

-Manual Testing -Postman -MySQL -Java

- Test Automation -Integration Testing -Ad-hoc Testing -Smoke Testing -Eclipse -SIT Testing -Regression Testing -Test Case Creation -JIRA -Maven -Putty -Defect Tracking -Cross-functional -Team leadership -Problem-solving -Agile

-Continuous Learning

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ernst & Young | Kerala, India

June 2022 to June 2023

Senior, Software Tester

- Performed QA Analysis, test case preparation and test case execution for all sprint stories.
- Implemented test plan, requirement traceability matrix and test summary report.
- Managed end-to-end testing process, from requirement analysis to final delivery of the product.
- Verified integrity between front end and back end using SQL queries.
- Participated in sprint planning sessions, daily stand ups and retrospective meetings as part of Agile practices.
- Coordinated with the internal teams to ensure the quality of products delivered.

Tata Consultancy Services Limited | Kerala, India

Sep 2015 to June 2022

IT Analyst, Software Tester

- Implemented Test Automation Framework using Selenium, Java, TestNG, Apache POI,
 Extent Reports, Page Object Model and Cucumber, thereby helped the team to reduce the manual testing effort.
- Developed and executed test cases in postman for Api interfaces of the product.
- Executed functional, regression, smoke, sanity and integration testing for all new products.
- Managed test cases and defect tracking using Jira.
- Attended daily scrums and represented the testing team.
- Estimated and coordinated testing activities, ensuring minimal risk and maintaining product quality.
- Mentored junior testing members, provided guidance and support in testing.
- Defined regression test cases for the project and maintained traceability records back to the requirements.
- Utilized Jira to report software issues and monitor their resolution status, verified bugs in new releases.

EDUCATION

MSC Computing Sept 2023 – Sept 2024

University Of Northampton, Northampton, United Kingdom

Bachelor of Technology, Electrical & Electronics Sept 2011 – June 2015

Mahatma Gandhi University, Kerala, India